CAROL KANG

UX DESIGNER | FRONTEND DEVELOPER | PROJECT MANAGER

BROOKLYN, NY
917-916-3813
CAROLKANG@ME.COM
LINKEDIN
GITHUB | SWE PORTFOLIO

EXPERIENCE

L'Oreal, New York

Commercial Planning Manager for Luxe Division Dec 2020 - Apr 2022

- Led quarterly budgeting, trend planning and forecast processes for eight Designer Fragrances brands with senior leadership.
- > Published monthly summary of each brand's sell-in and sell-out performance against budget/trend, with commentary on retailer standout performances and business drivers.
- Overhauled DF's sales forecast system by interviewing users/stakeholders, creating prototypes, and performing user tests, resulting in 50% reduction in low-value work for sales submissions, and faster and more accurate data consolidation for Head of Sales. Improved alignment between Sales, Marketing, Demand Planning, and Finance teams.

Sales Administration Manager for Designer Fragrances Group Apr 2020 - Dec 2020

- Created the Brand Sales & Marketing tool for tracking sales, marketing initiatives and ROI, informed by user research to ensure ease of use for senior leadership. Conducted training sessions for Marketing teams on how to effectively use the tool.
- > Contributed to the Prada Acquisition Preparation Team by identifying and addressing department needs to ensure a smooth transition to L'Oreal.

Retail Operations Manager for Atelier Cologne Dec 2018 - Mar 2020

- Successfully transitioned the newly acquired brand's retail stores to L'Oreal's processes and policies. Advocated for the retail sales team's needs by identifying their requirements and effectively communicating them to the IT team. This increased efficiency and enabled them to provide a better customer experience to increase sales.
- > Led the project management of retail initiatives, collaborated closely with cross-functional teams, coordinated timely communication between teams to achieve project goals.

PROFILE

My primary focus as a UX designer is to craft exceptional user experiences that optimize efficiency and create frictionless ways of working. I strive to create an experience that not only meets user needs but also drives better business outcomes.

SKILLS

Project Management

Figma, Information Architecture, Wire-framing, Prototypes, User Research

Javascript, CSS, HTML, React, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, Node.js, REST API, PostgreSQL, Python, Github

EDUCATION

School of the Art Institute of Chicago, BFA

General Assembly

Software Engineering Immersive Program AUG 2022 - NOV 2022

Google | Coursera Foundations of UX

JAN 2023

Atelier Cologne, New York

Commercial Operations Director

JUL 2011 - NOV 2018

- Built an operations foundation for Wholesale, E-Commerce, Brick & Mortar sales, encompassing finance and control procedures, demand and sales planning.
- > Implemented processes and designed internal tools based on feedback and testing from cross-functional teams to support the rapid growth and organizational needs of the business.
- > Developed KPI dashboards through a process involving user feedback, wireframing, and prototyping.

Operations & Analytics Consultant for Emerging Beauty Brands [Juice Beauty, Supergoop, Zents]

JUN 2010 - JUL 2011

Evaluated business practices and provided a strategy program to improve efficiency and support growth. Created framework for sales and KPI reporting, and tools to streamline business practices to be used for internal operations.

LVMH Perfumes & Cosmetics, New York

Director of Retail Operations for Fresh

JAN 2007 - MAY 2010

- > Established a retail organizational structure to maximize productivity, support growth and contain costs.
- Planned retail sales planning and budgets to ensure maximum ROI, business performance analysis and productivity reporting, customer behavior analysis.
- > Led retail expansion of eight stores.
- > Led brand's data initiatives, such as POS client capture program, traffic counter program.

Manager of Retail Operations for Fresh

JAN 2005 - DEC 2006

- > Standardized operational standards for retail division.
- > Developed programs and led trainings for Store Managers for all Retail systems and apps
- > Published monthly reports on sales and marketing analysis to provide critical insights for senior leadership to make informed decisions on the direction of the business.